foreign
that's not a good start
um that ain't good hello and welcome
back to another episode of hermit
crafter I'm just gonna repair this
little little bit of damage here first
there we go all fixed up and as you can
see I've actually got a bunch of cows
because I've been farming up some
leather and actually let's just pop some
music on because what we need to do
today is pretty important we're actually
going underneath this very fire pit that
just blew up now if we go down here you
can see that there's actually quite a
lot of work that needs doing this space
is completely empty but you can see that
I've placed a few bits of dirt basically
we're going to be making this into our
secret tunnel underneath area 77 but I
want this to look more of the part so
we're going to kick off today's episode
with a time lapse of us creating this
area
so it might not be particularly obvious
what I'm going to be doing here but as
you can see I'm slowly replacing the big
Square rectangular box with some very
messy dirt and coarse dirt because I
want this build to really tell the story
of what's going on here and that mainly
involves creating something that looks
more natural not in terms of like
Minecraft natural but natural in terms
of I've dug out a big hole underground
and there's loads and loads of dirt I
think it actually looks much much better
if it's just the one block it actually
you can see that I've made this all by
hand and then I wanted to add all the
details how did we dig this hole well we
made some big machines some diggers that
are more modern and not really that
hippie like so it really feels like a
secret underground operation that you
might expect in like a Bond film or
something so we're hiding this from
everyone and I think this looks pretty
cool I may have gone a little bit
overboard and I've actually had a few
more ideas since the time lapse it took
a really long time but look at this if
you use the grindstone like this one
after the other you can really make it
look like Caterpillar ties does doesn't
that look awesome as a little detail on
this particular Digger so I've actually
you know built these two diggers to make
it look like we're actually Excavating
under here now this very much isn't
hippie at all this is um this is pretty
modern technology digging our way into
area 77 I actually haven't started the
tunnel yet that's what we're going to do
now but I actually have a plan just in
case the boys come looking so we're
going to make a bit of a security door
at least so that if Doc and star do
happen to come looking at what we're
doing here and they happen to find the
very obvious hole in my RV
they're not gonna find anything that
they can get into so we're gonna create
a redstone door here yep you heard me a
redstone door and I've actually got a
design from none other than our mustache
friend Mumbo jumbolio so thank you Mumbo
for the design and we're about to make
it right here now this episode's
probably gonna have a lot of time
lapsing in because I actually want to
make a really like a lot of progress
today I want to make sure we get a lot
done because the hippie area our little
hippie commune has well it's got a bit
of catching up to do on the area 77
business because scar has been very very
busy building and doc has been very very
busy breaking minecraft so the hippies
have a long way to go and I'm gonna
start by making this tunnel a reality
because actually it might not seem like
the hippie commune is very far away but
in terms of a tunnel we've got a lot to
dig but like I said said first we need
to protect this with a little Redstone
door well maybe maybe not too little I'm
gonna make a four by four door that I
saw on mumbo's video because it's it's
actually really really awesome and I
think it will fit really well if I make
it all out of dirt and hide it properly
so let's time lapse this little creation
of some Redstone this is the first time
I've ever Redstone something that's not
really a build it's you know Redstone
and I desperately want to get better at
it so I'm gonna take every opportunity I
can to try and install some more
Redstone into my videos to try and get
better at it even if it just me starting
off by copying some other designs just
so I can learn I'm so shocked that I
didn't mess it up and it worked first
time this door is so fast okay so I've
actually got a really cool idea on how
we can activate this to open it I just
need to make sure I've got enough space
and the Redstone that I do make doesn't
interfere with anything so I'm going to
play it real safe and I'm going to make
it like a couple blocks away so
observers are great because they detect
pretty much anything and if I pop a
sticky piston here and then a redstone
block right there if I then I if I then
hoe this block here like that
did I put this the wrong way didn't I
I still I still got a lot to learn I
still got a lot to learn there you go it
then creates a t flip floppy a floppy T
flop a flop flop T flop T flop I'm gonna
make my own Redstone words up and see
how they catch on right so we've got
ourselves a t flip-flop or as I prefer
to call them a t flop
and then all I've got to do is send this
Redstone signal all the way up to this
bit up here shouldn't be too difficult
at all
there's there must be easier ways of
doing that oh dear
uh somehow I've powered only half of it
I thought what I was doing was so simple
yes I did it
look at that we've got ourselves uh uh
uh we've got ourselves a pretty awesome
door
all right now all we have to do is cover
this up in a nonchalant way using coarse
dirt and normal dirt just like
everywhere else
I hope that oh I better not touch any of
it otherwise it might get it might get
stuck and break the door
but as long as this looks like
everything fits I'm pretty sure that you
won't be able to tell that this is here
at all
I think the scariest thing about this
entire thing is not that I actually
managed to do this Redstone the main
thing is that I kind of understand why
it works I understand The Observers and
all of this and how it all updates I
actually understand why this door works
that doesn't mean I would be able to
actually design something like this
myself don't get me wrong this is a
genius design
but I actually understand it and I
learned quite a lot just from building
this and just trying to understand I
spent ages just looking at The Observers
and wondering wait so why does that
power that why does this power this Etc
and what maybe one day I'll be able to
make my own piston door and it is
totally covered and although it might be
obvious to us we know that there's
something there but in the grand scheme
of things under here where everything is
meant to look like it's being dug out so
you just have to know which block it is
this one you right click it with a hoe
and then it releases the door for you to
then enter and I think it might actually
close behind you no this would stay
there until someone walked over it but I
don't know if that that automatically
closes it so you can open it with a
right click and then you just jump on it
to close it or walk over it repeatedly
move Sprint on it there we go that's how
you close the door easy peasy but I
think that's probably more than enough
time spent underground I'm gonna have to
continue this long tunnel in the next
episode but we have successfully I
didn't walk over that
I think that did it by itself
that's a bit worrying the door can shut
behind you
I might need to make it activatable from
the other side but still it's it's
really awesome okay let's get out of
here because it's actually getting a
little bit claustrophobic down here
I did actually promise that I would tell
you about this thing over here the giant
Circle and I actually saw some of your
guys's comments and they were pretty
accurate but I won't tell you which ones
they are just yet what we need to do is
actually make this cylinder go pretty
deep down probably about 30 or 40 blocks
or so not entirely sure but yeah it
needs it needs to go down quite away so
again I told you that there was going to
be a lot of time lapsing in this video
because there's a lot of things that
need doing and they're pretty grindy
things to do so let's start the time
lapse of me digging this circular hole
all the way down
this will be probably the last time
lapse of this particular episode however
I thought I would share the creation of
this Silo just because time lapsing
something like this where you're digging
a big hole it's very satisfying to watch
so it's not gonna last very long and
it's not going to go even all the way to
bedrock but I think it looks really cool
nonetheless
oh my goodness
I've accidentally created a slime farm
in this Silo I I finished digging it and
it's pretty deep and I'm pretty happy
with it but I have a feeling it might
actually end up being much bigger in the
long run because what I'm going to be
making in here is actually a distraction
a distraction from area 77 or to
distract the guys in area 77 so
obviously this looks very suspicious and
that's kind of the point I want them to
be focusing on this stuff rather than
what we're doing under there hello
what there's clearly been a thunderstorm
because there's ow there's the the
skeletons of the Apocalypse or whatever
they're called
get rid of him and then we're in hey
oh my good wait whoa whoa whoa whoa
yo no no no no no no
I was just what is going on what are you
doing in our farm hey hey it's it's all
good it's all good we're hippies we're
we're all friends here they're they're
just bailing what have they done
what have they done
apart from leave a bow
they didn't go under I hope they I hope
they didn't go under if they only got
here they probably just saw this lovely
garden and you know what they're welcome
it to it they're welcome to look around
this lovely peaceful garden because
there's absolutely nothing suspicious
about it however there is something very
suspicious about
my my van I should hide this better I
need to come up with a better way to
hide this in fact right now I think I
need to I need to hide oh they might
have already seen it but it just in case
they haven't if that I didn't know that
they were snooping around let's just
cover this up real quick it's gonna be
super annoying to get in in and out of
this van now
this door is the worst thing right
let's get rid of that there we go so
it's hidden a little bit more now but I
have a feeling that they might have seen
things I don't know
I don't know I'm just gonna hope that
they
they only saw the garden there anyway
what I was gonna say before I was rudely
interrupted is do you remember from the
very very beginning of this series which
was over a year and a half ago we had a
horse called Jack skellabone and I
haven't seen one of these in a long time
can I feed him Bones I need a saddle I
need a saddle so that I can keep him can
keep him in the hippie commune hold on I
actually have leads having a nap what
are you up to
oh yeah okay so they're just playing
dumb
don't don't act like I didn't see you
don't act like I didn't see you
snooping snooping around this is a place
of Peace everyone is welcome
as Ren Bob would say welcome man or
something along those lines there we go
I crafted a couple of leads
doc doc just said something that makes
me makes me a little uneasy as you have
nothing to hide over there right just as
we do nothing to see here and keep the
music down
uh they I don't I'm gonna have to check
if they see something wait can I not
lead a horse
can you not oh man because it's tamed
Maybe
okay I'm gonna just need to get a saddle
from somewhere I found a saddle from my
base there we go you can't put armor on
these ones but look at this
we got we got our skeleton horse back
this is amazing I I don't know what I'm
gonna do with him we're gonna we're
gonna keep him we're gonna keep him in
the hippie commune
this is amazing
it's a shame I can't lead them
I guess I'm just gonna leave him right
here
oh this is so cool
I'm gonna need a new name for him though
this isn't Jack skellabone this is a
this is a new guy so give me your name
suggestions for my skeleton horse in the
comments down below and I'll choose my
favorite out of all of them now that Ren
is actually online I desperately need to
think he's actually just over there so
I'm gonna go and hop into a call with
him and discuss what I've just seen the
two the two guys coming in here and
taking a little peek around so hold on
let me just uh get hold of Ren are you
okay Ren I I've got some news bad news
green we have an emergency situation
yeah I was about to say I've Just Seen
yeah I've Just Seen Doc and Scar
skulking around in here
I reckon they've seen some of the hippie
secrets that I've been building
yeah you didn't see them by chance run
off with what used to be a hyperspace
inducing nuclear reactor did you I've
been staring at this the entire time
talking to you and I had I didn't
realize at all that it was gone uh no
okay so that's what they took that's
what that's what they were here for it's
bad news for rain Bob man he loves
flying around in hyperspace he's gonna
be one sad hippie let me tell you yeah
but didn't didn't you steal that in the
first place though to be fair uh
well brain Bob stole it I had nothing to
do with it about it I don't know what
you're talking about they're totally
justified in taking that away from you
because you stole it the scar in the
first place
yeah I mean look we've got problems
they've clearly got eyes on what we're
doing
um so you want to steal let me get this
straight you want to steal back what
they what you stole from them yeah
foreign okay right so there's a lot of
there's a lot of stealing going on yes I
suppose you as yeah I suppose you were
just using it to fly around but still I
think that's like there's no crime here
they're just taking back what belonged
to them in the first place
yeah well listen they obviously have
eyes around here there's spies in
abundance yeah dude have you seen this
yeah have you seen the the little green
truck they've got over here yeah we need
to do something about this man well you
know I'm a little bit ahead of you
actually on that front here let me show
you let me show you my little secret
this is what I was terrified that I
thought they had found because they even
said in the chat afterwards like we you
we know you're hiding something
um so I I panicked and I I hid it it's
not it's not particularly well hidden
you can see oh yeah this is
um but if you come down here
I have been working on a little project
to make our way into area 77 because I'm
trying to get my time machine back look
at this isn't it awesome what this is
insane yeah man this is awesome
okay I'm making a tunnel to uh to tunnel
on this area 77 and here let me show you
I made it like dude I've even done some
Redstone let's check this out okay
whoa wait a minute when did you learn to
do your Redstone this doesn't make sense
yeah I totally copied a tutorial but
that's not the point I ran wait wait a
minute
oh this is amazing there's so there's no
switch on the other side you're stuck oh
okay
that's it's cold here
oh yeah so that's going to be the tunnel
right it's gonna I'm gonna I'm gonna
need your help actually because it's
quite a long way to get to area 77. Okay
and then hopefully we can break through
get into area 77 and take back what's
ours or you take back what you stole in
the first place okay makes sense
um I've also been working underground
and well we're gonna have to get out of
here first though so yeah straight up
straight up the ladder straight up the
ladder okay particularly well hidden
yeah um I've been working on a little
bit of covert operation myself right
trying to make sure that they don't see
what we're doing around here yeah so
it's not cold
I just saw your Facebook it's all the
way up here down there but I know I had
no idea what you were doing yeah bit of
a secret entrance right so we got lots
of cool things coming up we don't want
them to see it there's no ladder and I
thought yeah you're just gonna have to
you're just gonna have to just fall yep
yeah I saw you working down here but I
didn't know what you were doing I was
just like yeah I'll leave them to it you
bet you made a mushroom
yeah it's this is a meeting room that's
the idea this is a visiting room yeah
I'm eating mushroom should we say see
what I did you've got some maps over
there as well of area 77 apparently
rainbob traded them from Cub I think
they're pictures from the drones
um of area 77. they don't actually work
by the way they're broken
um I guess he wanted some beetroots but
I did I don't know look my Silo I've
actually built that I need to explain
the whole Silo thing as well we're not
very good at communicating I didn't know
you were doing this you didn't know what
I was doing we need to communicate
better
oh that's what the stream room's all
about my dude I have lots of meetings
down here all right all right all right
yeah this is definitely outdated because
I've already built more than just that
Circle and I'm pretty sure scar has made
some crazy and I mean crazy
Cliffs along that side
so I mean it's what we can clearly see
though is a clear line between the Vans
and this thing called time experiments
oh nice yeah that that works right I
mean we might yeah we might we have to
make sure somehow that we don't
overshoot it and stuff but I mean yeah I
mean I can I can see us making like a
full tunnel system right under area 77
like tons of them and we'll just make
our way to all of these places very very
nice Minecart area anyway let's okay so
what's the inside of the mushroom I'm
dying to know
welcome to the stream room
the actual room or is this temporary
this is temporary but we can hatch a
couple of hippie plans in here for now
okay um well my my plan at the moment is
to dig a tunnel as I showed you straight
under area 77 to break in but to keep
them as we already know they're walking
around having a look at what we're doing
I want to distract them as much as
possible from the key Target so it's I
want to avoid them going down into my
industrial excavation so I'm making some
like big obvious things above ground for
them to go oh look look what are they
look at what they're doing and I've
built a giant Silo and I would actually
love to get your help on it because it's
quite a big very nice yeah I feel like
we could we could definitely make a lot
of like Minecraft farms like Flower
Farms sugarcane Farms all of the natural
products that all fits in with our
hippie theme and then I agree we can
fill up this Silo so my plan with this
Silo okay is to build a Giant RV
sticking up in the air and they will
start theorizing about what it's going
to be I'm not gonna I'm not gonna reveal
all my cards yet but we're gonna have a
job sticking up out of this hole and
that should keep them fairly distracted
while we create even more distractions
with all the farms and stuff they'll
have no idea what we're really up to
yeah
well that sounds great I mean I've
already got this Farm thing going on I
think next up maybe I can throw together
a little bit of a commune around here
you know some tents or something maybe
we can get some actual hippies here
let's come and live here you know and
it'll look really innocent like nothing
is going on yeah other than the Giant RV
coming out the silo in 1.14 someone
discovered that you can you can get
pillages and if you get them to shoot uh
of a villager but you put snow in the
way they lose their crossbows and then
they become peaceful I think I saw it in
one of x's videos they just become
peaceful and they walk around and the
Cub showed it as well so it's totally
possible they just walk around and do
nothing they're just totally peaceful so
we could like do we could have them as
our citizens to show that this is like a
really peaceful
area I don't know we can make a Pillager
Village
we're gonna turn pillages into hippies
is what you're suggesting
the pillages
genius that is actually a great plan
okay well I'm gonna crack on with some
of that money that sounds uh that's a
lot of fun yeah I think we got a solid
plan here yeah sweet also llama
who knows
ow no bad Ren help